<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>doingbird</title>
    <description>magazine</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 14:15:58 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 14:15:58 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>‘Stranger Things’ Star Finn Wolfhard On Cool Nerds &amp; Flying Cars</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following in the footsteps of such classic shows as Freaks and Geeks and Tracey McBean, Stranger Things reminds us that nerds are actually the coolest. The modern-day masterpiece, which turned our world upside down when it aired on Netflix earlier this year, is also responsible for unearthing a group of kids who are restoring our faith in humanity by proving the future is in very good hands — including 13-year-old Finn Wolfhard, who plays the relatably awkward Mike Wheeler. Talking on the phone from Los Angeles, Wolfhard weighs in on the likelihood of flying cars (low) and his decidedly weird generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2-5efe07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2-5efe07.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUCY JONES: How have your friends at school reacted to the Stranger Things hype?&lt;/strong&gt;
FINN WOLFHARD: I think they’re handling it as well as I want [them to]! I don’t want them to be freaking out, because I try to be as normal as possible when I come home. It’s sort of great because my friends are a dose of reality, like, “Shut up, just come play video games with us. Stop being so self-centred.” And I think I need that. They all watch the show but they’re fine with it. They know I’m just a nerd [laughs], I’m just doing my job and they get that, which is very cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were friends with some of the kids before you started filming, right? What was the vibe like once you got on set?
It was so cool because Caleb, Gaten and I, we all made friends. We instantly bonded and the first scene we shot was the first scene in the show, which is the D&amp;amp;D scene. I think that was the most fun and memorable scene to shoot, because it was like we’d known each other all our lives, even though we’d only known each other for, like, two months. It was very cool how we all came to set and just jumped in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From showrunners the Duffer Brothers to Winona Ryder it’s an amazing team. Who did you learn the most from?&lt;/strong&gt;
I took a page from everyone’s book. I took a lot from Caleb because he’s a very good dramatic actor, and Gaten’s a good comedic actor because he just goes with it. But I think I learned the most from Shawn Levy and the Duffers. Shawn was our executive producer and the director for episodes three and four. I’m very interested in filmmaking and I’d love to direct. There are some sets where you can’t even go to Video Village [an area on set with portable monitors] and watch your own tape, which sucks and there’s not enough freedom, but that’s the job. On our set it was very supportive. After I’d done my scenes they’d be doing a scene with either Winona or Natalia [Dyer, who plays Mike’s sister Nancy] and they’d let me come back and learn the ropes of directing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/3-9c3b1c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3-9c3b1c.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The relationship between you and Eleven, played by Millie Bobby Brown, is a central part of the story. What’s your take on it?&lt;/strong&gt;
I think Millie and I are very comfortable with ourselves, which is really cool. We had a bond from the beginning, because I think Millie said one time that she’s crazy and I’m the straight man, but it’s sort of the opposite in Stranger Things because she completely downplays it; she’s amazing in it. I think we both knew that we were just doing our jobs and acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What impact has growing up in public — and on the internet — had on you?&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s hard getting used to that but I’ve come up with a solution on how not to stress myself out, and that’s literally just staying away from it. There’s not really a point in staying on social media 24 hours a day because then that’s just another thing you have to do, you know? That’s just another job that I have to control and sometimes I don’t need that, so I end up playing my guitar or hanging out with friends. Sorry, my dog’s barking…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What kind of dog do you have?&lt;/strong&gt;
An Irish Setter. She’s red but she’s really dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think sets your generation apart from past generations?&lt;/strong&gt;
I think it’s definitely a weirder generation; it’s very abnormal when you compare it to the 80s or 90s. This is obviously what entertainment is now — with all these streaming services you can just watch something whenever you want, and that’s insane when you think about it. What’s cool about Stranger Things and what was so crazy and unexpected, was that it got so popular so fast and people can watch the whole thing by themselves like that. It’s definitely the route show business is going to go in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/4-49c40a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4-49c40a.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you’ve been working on an adaptation of Stephen King’s It, too.&lt;/strong&gt;
Yeah. It was the best summer of my life. I made new friends and they’re like my family now. It was definitely the most intense set I’ve been on, but it was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you call yourself a superstitious or spiritual person?&lt;/strong&gt;
I wouldn’t call myself a spiritual person. I go to church sometimes [laughs]. But I definitely believe in some sort of supernatural elements in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You mentioned you play guitar. What kind of music are you into at the moment?&lt;/strong&gt;
I have sort of a wide view. I can listen to electronic — I like M83 and Phoenix — but I also like old music like David Bowie or Lou Reed or The Beatles; I love Nirvana. There’s this alternative rock band called Playdate that I’ve been getting into recently. My friend Malcolm is an amazing drummer and my friend Alya is an amazing guitarist so we jam together, bounce ideas off each other. I’d love to record some music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you picture the future?&lt;/strong&gt;
Ah gee, that’s sorta hard. I mean change is obviously going to happen. I like how things are today. Technology is getting updated all the time, I can deal with that, but in the next ten years I don’t see a huge change from now. If my lifestyle doesn’t change then I’m pretty sure I’ll be fine [laughs]. If there’s a drastic change where dinosaurs are flying in the sky or flying cars, that’ll be weird, but I don’t think that’ll happen, knock on wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you hope humans will achieve within the next 50 years?&lt;/strong&gt;
I won’t go into detail because I’m 13 and I can’t vote yet, but I have good ideas… I’m a good reader of people and [some] people don’t have a good personality and they don’t have a good idea about human rights and learning how to treat people as you want to be treated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most excited about that’s coming up in your future?&lt;/strong&gt;
I’m excited for season two. I start in two weeks in North Carolina, we do the table read and I’m really excited to see the new characters and the new people that have been cast. And I’m excited to see some of the things that I’ll be attached to soon. I’m doing a music video for one of my favourite bands in Toronto called Pup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were just at the White House, right? How was that?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yeah [laughs], it was pretty surreal and amazing. I met Barack Obama and he was the coolest guy ever, and obviously he’s a world leader but he watched the show with his wife and kids and he loves the show and was talking to us about it. He was very, very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 13:21:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/stranger-things-star-finn-wolfhard-on-cool-nerds-and-flying-cars/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/stranger-things-star-finn-wolfhard-on-cool-nerds-and-flying-cars/</guid>
        
        
        <category>features</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So real: look inside the exhibition of lifelike sculptures from the past 700 years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Like Life” is mostly stunning, magnetically so. How could it not be? It’s all about the human body and face — the most transparently accessible, frequently depicted subjects in the history of western art — and the human desire to wrest both into lifelike three dimensions, from the classical Greeks to Degas to Robert Gober.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show presents around 120 mostly realistic figurative sculptures, religious personages, manikins, artist’s dummies, anatomical models, dolls and automatons, including a brand-new one from the Polish-born artist Goshka Macuga that natters on about the state of the world for 38 minutes with quotations from Shakespeare and “Blade Runner.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, this time the Met’s design staff has triumphed over the Breuer’s recalcitrant galleries. Filmy white curtains often substitute for walls, filtering light and mixing the silhouettes of sculptures and viewers in fleeting tableaus. The show is spaciously arranged with thought and elegance, and full of engrossing groupings and pairings. Jeff Koons’s immense, overexposed porcelain “Michael Jackson and Bubbles” benefits from its juxtaposition with an 18th-century Meissen set-piece “The Judgement of Paris.” The most touching duo may be Augustus Saint-Gaudens’s memorial marble portrait bust of Louise Adele Gould beside the painted wax version her grieving husband also commissioned: softer material and color collude to hauntingly lifelike effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIKE LIFE: SCULPTURE COLOR, AND THE BODY (1300-NOW) IS ON NOW UNTIL 22 JULY AT THE MET BREUER, MANHATTAN. METMUSEUM.ORG&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 12:47:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/so-real-look-inside-the-exhibition-of-lifelike-sculptures-from-the-past-700-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/so-real-look-inside-the-exhibition-of-lifelike-sculptures-from-the-past-700-years/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Art</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner's Guide to Meditation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard people rave about meditating, you’ve read articles about CEOs and celebrities claiming to be meditation devotees, and you’ve made the decision to incorporate it into your daily routine. But how to begin?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, understand what meditation is. It’s not about making your mind blank or chanting a mantra — meditation is about awareness without distraction, whether that’s focusing on your breath or concentrating on a mantra or opening yourself up different thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Really. It might be hard to believe that something that sounds that simple can help regulate mood, lower blood pressure, bolster your immune system, and improve your sleep, but meditation isn’t that easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the things on your plate — work, boyfriends and girlfriends, cleaning your house, flatmates, friends, figuring out what show to watch on Netflix next. Now imagine trying to ignore all that and turn your brain off. Tricky, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most things in life, meditation requires patience and practice, but putting in the time and effort can have a positive impact on your physical, mental, and emotional health. Here are some of our top tips for meditation newbies so you can start clearing your mind and reaping the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-an-intention&quot;&gt;Set an intention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting an intention before you meditate helps focus the individual practice and guide your greater relationship with meditation. Stay positive, and focus on an achievable goal — then, when you begin meditating, surrender it. While it’s important to have goals, acknowledging what you don’t have control over and the infinite ways your intention can manifest can help your attitude and outlook. It will also help remind you of what you want to accomplish. For example, if you want to start meditating, then there’s no excuse to start today.
Find somewhere comfortable: Create a quiet, distraction-free environment. Sit in a chair or on the floor in a cross-legged positions with the hands on the knees. You want to be focused on meditation, not pain in your back or extraneous sound. Just remember not to make it so comfortable you feel tempted to drift to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remember-your-spine&quot;&gt;Remember your spine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your spine controls every nerve and aspect of your body, and Indian thought maintains that’s where the seven chakras, where energy flows in our bodies, are located. It’s only natural you want to be conscious of it. Sit up straight by rolling your shoulders up and backward. Keep your head elevated above your heart. If you feel yourself slump or hunch, adjust accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice-your-breath&quot;&gt;Practice your breath&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wondering how exactly to meditate? Focus on the breath moving in and out, particularly in the area between your nostrils and upper lip, and bring your thoughts back to it whenever they start to get away from you. It doesn’t hurt that mindful breathing is one of the quickest ways to reduce anxiety and helps strengthen the mind-body connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-patient&quot;&gt;Be patient&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Becoming “good” at meditation doesn’t happen overnight, and if you find it frustrating, you’re not alone. Start with five minute intervals, and don’t criticize yourself if your thoughts wander or if you can’t stop thinking about an assignment at work — relax and return to your breath. If you’re really not feeling it one day, listen to your body and don’t push yourself. Meditation shouldn’t feel like a chore, and after consistent practice, it will soon be something you can return to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 15:06:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/a-beginners-guide-to-meditation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/a-beginners-guide-to-meditation/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
