<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>doingbird</title>
    <description>magazine</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 17:37:58 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 17:37:58 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guide to Essential Oils (Part 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Incorporating essential oils into your routine can welcome a variety of benefits, from better sleep to clearer skin. Last week, we covered the basics of essential oils: now, we want to share our favourite oils and why we always make sure to keep them on hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lavender:&lt;/strong&gt; This is basically the OG essential oil, sparking French chemist René-Maurice Gattefossé’s interest in them when it healed a burn on his hands. Thanks to its anti-inflammatory properties, putting a few drops of lavender oil on injured skin will be incredibly soothing, while a few dabs anywhere on your body can produce a calming effect. For a good night’s sleep, put some on your pillow — it doesn’t hurt that it will make your bed smell amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oregano:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to its anti-microbial properties, oregano oil is a powerhouse. It can kill fungus, bacteria, and help you kick a cold without needing any meds from the chemist. However, because it’s so strong, you’ll want to use it in moderation. A few drops on an infected area can help clear up things like athlete’s foot or other external fungi; if you’re ingesting it, only taking one drop with water and make sure not to continue use for more than a week at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peppermint:&lt;/strong&gt; There are few things quite as refreshing as mint, and peppermint oil is no exception. Able to do everything from support digestion to boosting energy and sharpening your focus, it’s also a more natural solution to bad breath than other mouthwash. Apply it topically to help ease sore muscles or add one drop to warm water to assuage any illness or digestive symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grapefruit:&lt;/strong&gt; Raise your hand if you’ve ever felt personally victimised by cellulite. Grapefruit oil wants you to put that hand down. Not only does it support your metabolism, but it also helps reduce cellulite. Combine it with coconut oil and rub it on any impacted areas, or add a few drops to a glass of water and drink it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rose:&lt;/strong&gt; Attention, beauty gurus. Rose oil is the secret you’ve been waiting for — from reducing skin inflammation to creating glowing skin, it’s the perfect addition to your arsenal and a few drops can just be combined with the moisturizer you already use. The only downside? Beauty doesn’t come cheap — it usually runs at about $1000 for 15 ml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eucalyptus:&lt;/strong&gt; Just smelling eucalyptus can be invigorating, and using the oil can be a great way to refresh and purify your body. It’s also a natural treatment for respiratory problems, while combating exhaustion or mental fatigue. Given its anti-microbial properties and stimulating scent, many people use it as an air freshener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also mix and match different oils to enhance their properties, or combine with a base oil (we’re big fans of coconut oil) to put in body products like massage oil or lotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using essential oils are a great supplement to a healthy diet and lifestyle. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, our plant-powered meals are equally nutritious and delicious to keep you feeling sexy, strong, healthy, and happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 21:44:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/guide-to-essential-oils-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/guide-to-essential-oils-part-2/</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>oils</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There Are How Many Different Types of Yoga?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We consider ourselves dedicated yogis — after all, there aren’t many activities that give you a great workout while putting equal focus on your emotional health. Since yoga is all about accepting where you are and finding an exercise that’s best for your body and needs, there is, naturally, a wide range of different styles, from what you might traditionally think of to the more spiritual. We’ve rounded up some of the most common yoga practices to help you demystify the various types and what they involve so you can go forth and find your perfect practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hatha&lt;/strong&gt;
Essentially all yoga class you’ll find fall under the umbrella “hatha yoga.” Encompassing almost every type of modern practices, hatha is one of six original yoga branches. If you see it advertised, it should mean your bread and butter class — think traditional postures and breathing techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashtanga&lt;/strong&gt;
Ashtanga classes are highly structured, moving through asana series where each student must master the pose in each series before moving to the next. Yogis transition from pose to pose with each inhale and exhale — linking breath and movement this way is called a vinyasa (and ashtanga is the predecessor of vinyasa yoga).This can be a intensive practice and is not necessarily recommended for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bikram&lt;/strong&gt;
This is your standard hot yoga class. With the temperature cranked over 40 degrees and 40 percent humidity, it’s known to be great for weight loss, as well as improving circulation and boosting your metabolism. The heat can also help loosen your muscles so you can go deeper into certain poses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vinyasa&lt;/strong&gt; 
This is ashtanga adapted for Western health nuts. Instead of following the same sequence of poses, vinyasa, or power, varies from class to class and teacher to teacher. The flow will be rapid, integrating aerobics with ashtanga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yin&lt;/strong&gt; 
The yin to your yang — in this case, the relaxation to your strength-building routine. Also known as Taoist yoga, yin is a quiet, passive practice that emphasises lengthening muscles by sustaining postures for several minutes. You’ll get a deep stretch while cultivating a meditative breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kundalini&lt;/strong&gt;
Kundalini (or “serpent”) yoga is a bit different than your traditional flow. This practice focuses on stimulating the life force found at the base of your spine, which is imagined as a coiled serpent. Poses will be invigorating, aiming to awaken this energy supply and send it throughout your body. Many yogis believe it helps with spiritual growth and allows us to tap into our full creative potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iyengar&lt;/strong&gt;
Perhaps less common, this practice is a great one for those of all levels and ages. Also known by its moniker “furniture yoga,” it was developed by B.K.S. Iyengar and draws on props like straps, blocks, and harnesses to help you perfectly achieve an asana. It prioritises alignment over building up a sweat, but that doesn’t mean it’s easy — if you’re looking for something a little gentler, we’d still recommend sticking with yin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best complement to a yoga practice? Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt; plant-powered meals, which are as delicious as they are nutritious to help you feel healthy, happy, sexy, and strong. Namaste to that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 21:33:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/there-are-how-many-different-types-of-yoga/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/there-are-how-many-different-types-of-yoga/</guid>
        
        <category>yoga</category>
        
        <category>exercise</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        <category>fitness</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Four Benefits of Drinking Red Wine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wine has been a staple in cultures for centuries, but it wasn’t just as a way to unwind or the final touch for a romantic dinner — our ancestors also used it as medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something about red wine at the end of the week that is as close as you can get to a smile in a glass. It pairs just as well with a romantic dinner as it does with some quality me-time and a Netflix binge, but decades of research corroborate that the benefits extend beyond just helping you relax or delighting your taste buds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Makes Red Wine Your Friend&lt;/strong&gt;
Red wine contains quercetin and resveratrol, two powerful — and necessary — antioxidants. Resveratrol, also found in blueberries, peanuts, pistachios, and cranberries, helps promote circulate, which in turn aids cellular and tissue health and helps ward off premature aging. Quercetin — produced by certain plants in response to stressors like fungi or injury — has anti-inflammatory properties and can guard against damage from free radicals. Lowering inflammation in your body can be helpful with heart disease, arthritis, cancer, diabetes, autoimmune diseases, and more. Here are some of the other ways a limited consumption of red wine can act like a superfood:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stronger bones: Though excessive drinking can weaken bones and increase the likelihood of fractures, light to moderate red wine consumption has been found to improve bone mineral density (BMD). This can help reduce the risk of osteoporosis when we’re older, which makes us much more susceptible to injury.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sharper memory: Sure, alcohol and memory don’t always go hand in hand, but if you enjoy a glass of vino with dinner, you could be boosting your brain power. Trusty old resveratrol was found to preserve essential synapses that relay information between the brain and muscles. In addition to keeping things more supple, it can also restrict the development of a protein that’s associated with Alzheimer’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regulated blood sugar levels: Though supermarket wines can be loaded with added sugar, high-quality, organic red wine can actually make the movement of glucose through the small intestine more gradual, which reduces spikes in blood sugar levels. This means that it can be included in a diet plan for those with diabetes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healthy heart: Quercetin, resveratrol, and polyphenols can help slow down a build up of fats, cholesterol, and plaque in artery walls. A study in the International Journal of Molecule Medicine found this actually decreased mortality rates compared to people who abstained from red wine or chronic drinkers. Resveratrol can also help protect the heart from tissue damage while relaxing coronary arteries, which aids in preventing cardiovascular disease. Even better, it’s been found to boost the amount of HDL, or “good” cholesterol, in our bodies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that while a light consumption of red wine can have benefits both physical and mental, alcohol is a neurotoxin and should be limited to keep your brain and body healthy. If you’re in the middle of a detox, it’s best to avoid it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy a glass of red with one of our pre-packaged, plant-powered meals. At Soulara, we’re driven to bring you nutrient-packed, delicious food that will leave you happy, healthy, sexy, and strong. We’ll raise a glass to that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 08:26:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/four-benefits-of-drinking-red-wine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/four-benefits-of-drinking-red-wine/</guid>
        
        <category>alcohol</category>
        
        <category>diet</category>
        
        <category>detox</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>gut health</category>
        
        
        <category>Nutrition</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guide to Essential Oils (Part 1)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For more than 5,000 years, cultures worldwide have consistently agreed on a super-powered remedy: essential oils. Aromatherapy, or the use of essential oils, is a practice that has been relied upon to treat a range of ailments from skin conditions to bodily pain to cellulite. Bonus: some can even be used in cleaning your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here to walk you through essential oils, their history, and how you can incorporate them into your daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are essential oils?&lt;/strong&gt;
Essential oils are exactly what they sound like: oil extracted straight from the bark, flower, fruit, leaf, seed, or root, of a plant or tree and created via distillation (when oil and water-based compounds are separated via steaming). A lot of plant is required for one bottle, but just one drop can have a powerful impact on your health. Plants use essential oils to protect themselves from environmental damage, meaning you’re essentially harnessing the world’s most natural healing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Where did they come from? **
Cultures including the Chinese, Indians, Egyptians, Greeks, and Romans drew on the powers of essential oils for their medicinal or cosmetic uses. However, it wasn’t until René-Maurice Gattefossé burned his hand in 1928 that the practice became more mainstream. The French chemist treated his wound with lavender oil, and was inspired to delve deeper into studying the oils thanks to how well it healed him. He devoted himself to helping injured soldiers in World War I, but aromatherapy has since drifted into the worlds of alternative medicine, massages, and physical therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use them:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Topically: Because essential oils are so small, they can be absorbed into the bloodstream when placed on the skin. Putting a few drops onto different spots of the body can allow the oil to penetrate for a litany of therapeutic benefits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aromatically: Essential oils can also be absorbed when diffused in the air, thanks to the blood vessels in your lungs. Different oils have different properties, but if you’re stressed, opt for lavender. To boost your mood or energy, try peppermint or wild orange. Bonus: it will make your room smell amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orally: Ingesting essential oils is a great way to maximise their medicinal benefits. However, they are extremely potent so be sure to take only one to three drops at a time. Oils like peppermint, lemon, and frankincense should be taken with water and can be consumed on a more regular basis, while oils like clove and oregano, both of which have very powerful antibacterial properties, should be diluted and not taken for more than a week at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beauty products: Essential oils are popping up in many beauty and personal care products, and are a handy addition when you’re DIYing your own. We love popping some oils into home-made shampoo, lip balm, toothpaste, and even household cleaners  — you’ll be exposing yourself to their health benefits while knowing that what you’re using is free of any harsh chemicals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for the second part to our essential oils guide, which will explore some of the most common and how they can help with everything from weight loss to growing thicker hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;soulara.com.au&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, we’re committed to bringing you pre-packed dishes that are as healthy as they are delicious. Our plant-powered meals will leave you nourished, sexy, happy, and strong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 08:13:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/guide-to-essential-oils-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/guide-to-essential-oils-part-1/</guid>
        
        <category>oils</category>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>beauty</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Guide to Gratitude</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting on your wellness journey, it’s easy to focus on the physical: embracing a new workout regimen or cleaning up your diet, like our with our plant-based Soulara meals. However, it’s just as important to take care of your emotional self, and one of the best methods is by practicing gratitude everyday. Regular gratitude has been found to increase levels of happiness, energy, and focus, as well as lead to better sleep, lessened stress, and an ability to pursue bigger goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude journal:&lt;/strong&gt; People have been journaling throughout history, and whether you do or not, keep a separate gratitude journal next to your bed. Every night, write down a few things you are grateful for, focusing on the positives. It might seem difficult at first, but soon, finding even five things will be a piece of cake — bonus: you’ll be able to flip through and be reminded of all the great things that have happened to you. Stuck for how to start? Write about who inspires you or what has brought you happiness, comfort, or peace that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use kind words:&lt;/strong&gt; When we think of our friends, we’re usually incredibly supportive, though we can struggle to use those same affirmations with ourselves. Remember that you’re beautiful, strong, and deserving of love, and be gentle and kind to yourself when you’re having a hard day. You’ll find that the more respect you give yourself, the better you’ll be able to handle difficult or stressful situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write thank you notes:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the little things. With most of our mail these days being bills or junk, make someone’s day by taking just a few moments to thank them for something, no matter how small. It will help spread a culture of gratitude, while helping you retrain your brain to be more attuned to thankfulness and happiness. Also consider thanking people in person for kind actsby doing this regularly, you’ll start to see the positive in everyday situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditate:&lt;/strong&gt; Regularly meditating has a long list of scientific benefits, including decreasing metabolism, lowering blood pressure, improving your heart rate, and providing mental clarity. There are multiple types of meditation — consider cultivating a mindfulness practice, which focuses on appreciating who we are at each moment and teaching us how to be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenge yourself to a complain-free 24 hours: It might not sound that hard, but throughout an ordinary day, small complaints and pet peeves can really add up. A lot of the time, our complaints our automatic and are expressed not just through our words, but our thoughts and body language. This challenge can help you notice how you behave, speak, and think — whenever you catch yourself complaining, recognise it and try to find a positive spin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show your body how much you love it with our plant-based meals. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, our pre-packaged dishes are loaded with delicious ingredients and super-charged with nutrients so you feel like your healthiest, happiest, strongest, and sexiest self. Now there’s something to be grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 08:34:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/your-guide-to-gratitude/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/your-guide-to-gratitude/</guid>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>mental health</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prevent Muscle Soreness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats! You’ve hit the gym, the trail, or the mat, and you’re feeling refreshed and strong. While we can’t rave enough about regular exercise — along with the physical benefits, your mind will feel clearer and there’s nothing quite like that sense of accomplishment — we know working out has its drawbacks. Our least favourite? Getting hit with muscle soreness two or three days after trying out a new class or getting back into a routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That soreness actually has a name, and Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness (DOMS) can’t be blamed on lactic acid. Lactic acid has long been seen as the culprit for aches and pains, but new research has found that lactic acid levels return to normal after just an hour post-exercise. Instead, DOMS is caused by microscopic damage to muscles and the ensuing inflammation, usually from eccentric resistance (when your muscle is lengthened, such as when you’re lowering a weight or running downhill.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are plenty of ways to prevent DOMS so the only thing you’re feeling after your workout are endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat up:&lt;/strong&gt; Eating after a workout is vital for loading your bodies with the nutrients and protein that can help injured muscles, though this shouldn’t be used as an excuse to indulge on sweets or other treats. Instead, aim to eat carbohydrates, protein, and antioxidants. Carbs will help muscle growth, while protein assists with repair to the fibres. Antioxidants are your best bet against inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink up:&lt;/strong&gt; C’mon. Did you really think we’d put together a list that didn’t include good ol’ H20? All those carbs and protein you’re taking in need water to function properly. For a refreshing twist, add slices of cucumber and parsley to your glass, or a few squeezes of lemon juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treat yourself:&lt;/strong&gt; If you had the flu, you’d take some time to let your body heal. The same should be true with DOMS – get some beauty sleep, or go one step further and book yourself a massage. A gentle massage won’t just feel good, but could help activate genes that naturally fight inflammation. (Not that you need another excuse to make an appointment with your masseuse.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get foamy:&lt;/strong&gt; Whether or not you like your latte with foam, using a foam roller on each sore muscle can go a long way in reducing soreness. Bonus, it’s a great alternative if a massage isn’t an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hot ‘n cold:&lt;/strong&gt; Feel free to sing the Katy Perry song in your contrast shower, where you alternate between warm and cold water. Sure, it’s not the most relaxing, but it opens and closes blood muscles, great for inflammation and for stimulating your lymphatic system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for the perfect post-workout option? Our plant-based meals are packed with the nutrients your body needs to help your muscles recover and prep you for conquering your day. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, we aim to help you feel your happiest, healthiest, sexiest, and strongest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 08:29:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-prevent-muscle-soreness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-prevent-muscle-soreness/</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>exercise</category>
        
        <category>fitness</category>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's the Deal with Activated Charcoal?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of history’s greatest feuds is between Ayurvedic and Chinese medicine and contemporary health practices. But when it comes to activated charcoal, both sides finally have something to agree on. Activated charcoal — to clarify, it’s activated, not the stuff you use on a barbecue — dates back to 1550 but is still used as a powerful antidote, combating poisoning and other health concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes it so special?&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s the “activated” part of charcoal that matters. Substances — typically wood, coal, coconut shells, or bamboo, are heated at extraordinarily high temperatures (between 600-900 degrees C) without oxygen. The process creates char, which is then exposed to certain gasses, like argon and nitrogen, and heated again. The charcoal’s surface area dramatically expands and it becomes very porous, meaning it can bind to almost anything through a process called adsorption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negatively charged, studies have found that when consumed, it can absorb more than half of unwanted toxins in the gas by attracting the positive ions. It helps eliminate poison and contaminants, so much so that ER doctors regularly rely on it. This also makes it a strong tool against environmental toxins that we encounter in daily life. Taking it as a supplement can help improve your mood and energy while reducing bloating and helping cure hangovers, along with a host of other benefits — no wonder it’s been a beloved remedy for over 10,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take it orally: you can consume it in capsule or powder form to potentially assist with everything from gas to cholesterol levels, although it’s not recommended that you incorporate it as a regular supplement.  Instead, use it in moderation when you believe you’ve been exposed to toxins or you’ve had a rough weekend. Don’t take too closely to taking medication, as it can block their absorption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whiten your teeth: Charcoal is a superhero when it comes to removing bacteria, chemicals, dirt, and miscellaneous build-up, making it perfect for naturally whitening your teeth. Either mix high-quality charcoal with a small amount of water and swish in your mouth or use a toothpaste with charcoal in it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give yourself a facial: Charcoal has been popping up in beauty products for good reason. It will leave your skin soft and detoxed. You can DIY your own face mask, or purchase a pre-made one (just make sure they’re using high-quality ingredients)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a shower: Charcoal removes impurities in your hair just as it does in your skin, making your locks soft and shiny. You can purchase a charcoal shampoo, or simply sprinkle some into your current shampoo and wash as normal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purify your home: Just as charcoal can help clean up your body, it can strip the air of odors, chemicals, and allergens. Consider getting some charcoal bags so your house is as healthy as your diet. It also functions well as a water purifier, removing contaminants — tap water won’t have ever tasted so good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping activated charcoal on hand is just one aspect of a healthy lifestyle. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, plant-based meals are designed to be packed with nutrients and irresistible flavours, all delivered straight to your door.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:15:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/whats-the-deal-with-activated-charcoal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/whats-the-deal-with-activated-charcoal/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beating the Detox Flu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve just started to detox your body and you know feeling amazing is just around the corner. Your energy will be high, your skin will be flawless, and you might even shed some unwanted weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, reality’s not quite cooperating with expectations. You might even feel worse than when you started, but you’re not alone. The Detox Flu is a normal occurrence after you make a big shift in your diet and start eliminating certain foods to help your body feel healthier and stronger in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you make big dietary shifts, even if that’s just changing to eating plant-based meals, your body has to start ridding itself of all the toxins caused by inflammation-promoting foods, like sugar, gluten, dairy, alcohol, and caffeine. Since your system wants to heal, the process of cleaning itself up can be fast and intense, making you feel more lethargic, moody, bloated, and sometimes sick. Though the detox flu may be unpleasant, remember that it’s a sign your body is doing what it needs to do and after about a week or so, you’ll feel better than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, taking certain measures can help you lessen the impact of the symptoms. Here are some of our favourite ways to make the journey to health as painless as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let yourself sleep:&lt;/strong&gt; In today’s world, taking time to rest and sleep instead of working, working out, or spending time with friends can seem like we’re doing something wrong. However, sleep is a critical component of wellness, especially when your body is working so hard to rid itself of all those toxins. Go to bed earlier than usual, and listen to your body when it’s saying it’s tired
&lt;strong&gt;Dry brush:&lt;/strong&gt; Dry brushing — Gwyneth Paltrow is a fan — is an excellent way to help detoxify your lymphatic system, a key part of your immune system. It helps combat infections, bacteria, and cancer cells, while balancing fluid levels. It gets bonus points for making your skin softer and brighter
&lt;strong&gt;Eat more fat:&lt;/strong&gt; That may sound counterintuitive, but our bodies need the healthy kinds of fats, which will actually help your body regulate your metabolism, especially if it’s been sluggish. Slice an avocado over your breakfast, or take MCT oil, or coconut oil. They can both be blended into your tea to help improve mental clarity and energy
&lt;strong&gt;Drink lots of water:&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously, lots. You should be well-hydrated normally, but your glass-per-day quota should increase when you’re detoxing as it will help your body flush out toxins while avoiding nasty symptoms like headaches and body pain. 
&lt;strong&gt;Grab some magnesium:&lt;/strong&gt; Magnesium is a miracle mineral that most people are deficient in — don’t be one of them. You’ll struggle to find something magnesium can’t do, especially in the detox process. It can help with bloating, elimination, and your energy levels, while helping your mind and muscles relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to make an upgrade to your diet? At &lt;a href=&quot;https://soulara.com.au/&quot;&gt;Soulara&lt;/a&gt;, our plant-based meals are nutrient-packed so you can be your strongest, happiest, sexiest, and healthiest self.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:04:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/beating-the-detox-flu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/beating-the-detox-flu/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q&amp;A: Pia Jones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Though Pia Jones is now a nutritionist, naturopath, and psychologist at Brisbane’s integrated health clinic &lt;a href=&quot;rivertreehealth.com.au/&quot;&gt;River Tree Health&lt;/a&gt;, she didn’t always have the healthiest relationship with food. After struggling with anorexia as a teenager, she now is an advocate of integrative health and treating diet as nourishment. We chatted with Pia about the best way to care for our bodies on the go and how nutrition impacts our overall wellness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a bit more about your health journey. What led you to become a clinical naturopath and nutritionist?&lt;/strong&gt;
It was a six month stint living in a seaside town called Essouira in Morocco that my way of relating to food began to change and I also became really interested in herbal medicine. We would gather at lunch and dinner and eat fresh meals using only wholefood ingredients baked in huge tagines. Food was always shared, seated in a circle with huge chunks of freshly baked bread in our hands. Eating was a social activity, just as much as a nourishing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the connection between the brain and the body? Why is nutrition so important for overall wellness?&lt;/strong&gt;
We know that the gut and brain communicate with one another and if there is an imbalance in either one, the other is impacted. Vitamins, minerals and amino acids are the building blocks for our hormones and neurotransmitters, which are very powerful messengers in the body. Without good food, the body simply does not have the building blocks to manufacture these messengers that keep us happy and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does a healthy diet mean to you?&lt;/strong&gt;
A wholefood diet! I believe we have different needs and preferences based on genetics, intolerances, lifestyle, moral considerations and personal taste! However, eating a diet that places an emphasis on plant based options and minimises processed and pre packaged food is the number one priority. Plant-based foods contain enzymes that support the digestive process and provide fuel for good bacteria, whilst processed foods tend to be loaded with sugar and chemicals and encourage the overgrowth of bad bacteria in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can we best care for our health?&lt;/strong&gt; 
Gut care! A really simple way to ensure you have microbial diversity in the gut is to exercise in nature, eat wholefoods, have contact with pets, include some fermented foods in your diet, and manage your stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What development in the nutritional world most excites you?&lt;/strong&gt;
The team at River Tree Health love the developments in nutrition stemming from science.  For me specifically, it’s the science linking our gut microbiome to our brain health and the subsequent understanding that food impacts mood! The impact of nutrition on mental health is my biggest passion in life and I’m so excited to be a part of one of the few integrated medicine clinics in Australia that acknowledges the connection between nutrition, the gut and brain health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite Australian escape?&lt;/strong&gt;
Bring on the coast line! Sydney has a stunning harbour. I’m a massive boatie, so give me water and a boat and it’s happy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photograph by &lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelcarrello.photography&quot;&gt;Michael Carrello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:13:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/q-and-a-pia-jones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/q-and-a-pia-jones/</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>q&amp;a</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your New Health Weapon: Mindfulness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With our hectic schedules, it can seem like we’re rushing between work, drinks with friends, and a long list of other commitments, all while trying to look our best. We’re all about killing it at work, but just as important as taking the world by storm everyday is giving yourself a little TLC to boost yourself physically and mentally. Believe us, your beauty arsenal has yet to meet an ally like mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness, which encourages you to slow down and take in a moment with purpose, is shown to inspire self-love and self-acceptance. Essentially, you’re fully invested in what is happening at a given time and what you’re doing, without reacting too strongly to it. Sounds simple? Being completely present is a little trickier than it appears as we’re constantly swayed by demands, obligations, and other people, but the rewards are with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How exactly can mindfulness benefit you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re more aware of what we eat and what kind of nutrients we put into our bodies
*We pay more attention to how we communicate with ourselves, and what language we use when thinking about our bodies or our successes 
*We can be more forgiving with ourselves and be more open to what we might need to unwind, decompress, or celebrate 
*We become less stressed: a strong mindfulness practice can actually help your brain adapt to how it deals with stress, as well as regulating emotion regulation
*We’re better able to manage illness. We wish mindfulness could ward away the flu, but if you do get sick, meditation can help you deal with stress, bolster your emotional ability to cope with illness, and increase your energy levels. This is especially true for people suffering from chronic or potentially terminal illnesses
*It can help fight depression. One of the most powerful natural tools to counter depression and anxiety, mindfulness helps users distance themselves from, and understand, negative emotions so they are better able to manage depression symptoms 
*We’re strengthening our brain. Mindfulness is like a push-up for your brain, but without the exertion. Every time we complete an assignment, our brain readjusts itself to prepare for when we tackle a similar task. Mindfulness essentially tells it that we work better when calm, observant, and nonjudgmental, helping the brain rewire to accommodate that. A 2005 study found that those who practiced mindfulness had higher-performing cortexes, areas associated with functions like attention and sensory processing
*We look more radiant. When you’re taking care of your physical and mental state, you’re basically giving your body a free beauty treatment. When it comes to mindfulness and health, beauty really does come from the inside out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing a mindfulness practice may not be easy at first, but it’s not difficult to cultivate. Sit down or go for a walk while paying attention to what is going on around you. You can also combine it with yoga to ease into the practice. Most importantly, don’t think about being mindful. Simply let yourself experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While practicing mindfulness, nourish your body with our plant-based meals from Soulara. Delivered to your door, our meals are packed with super-powered ingredients to help you look as good as you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:56:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/your-new-health-weapon-mindfulness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/your-new-health-weapon-mindfulness/</guid>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>wellness</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>yoga</category>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
